A story you have to believe to see.
IF is a comedy, fantasy, family film directed by John Krasinski.
After discovering she can see everyone's imaginary friends, a girl embarks on a
magical adventure to reconnect forgotten imaginary friends with their kids.
Bea, played by Cailey Fleming.
Cal, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Dad / Marshmallow (voice), played by John Krasinski.
Grandmother, played by Fiona Shaw.
Blue (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Blossom (voice), played by Phoebe Waller-Bridge.
IF (also marketed as Imaginary Friends in some regions) is a 2024 American live-action animated fantasy comedy film written
and directed by John Krasinski, who also produced it alongside Allyson Seeger, Andrew Form, and Ryan Reynolds.
The film stars Cailey Fleming, Reynolds, Krasinski, and Fiona Shaw, with Alan Kim and Liza Colón-Zayas in
supporting roles, alongside the voice talents of Phoebe Waller-Bridge, Louis Gossett Jr., and Steve Carell.
Combining live-action and animation, the film follows a young girl (Fleming) who goes through a difficult experience and
begins to see everyone's imaginary friends who have been left behind as their children have grown up.
Development of the film began in 2019, with Krasinski set to
write and direct and Reynolds attached to star.
The rest of the cast joined between October 2021 and January 2022, and filming took
place in New York City between August of that year and May 2023.
IF was theatrically released by Paramount Pictures in
the United States on May 17, 2024.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed over
$190.3 million against a budget of $110 million.
The film explores themes of friendship, imaginary friend,
aftercreditsstinger, imaginary, live action and animation.
The tone is lighthearted.